<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Andrew Ladd</title>
 <link href="http://www.andrewladd.co/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.andrewladd.co/"/>
 <updated>2016-01-20T10:23:17-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.andrewladd.co</id>
 <author>
   <name>Andrew Ladd</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>My technological life</title>
   <link href="http://www.andrewladd.co/2016/01/09/i-heart-tech/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.andrewladd.co/2016/01/09/i-heart-tech</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been on a computer for almost as long as I remember. Back then, I used it almost solely for playing video games (so many hours of Commander Keen) and doodling on MS Paint. As the years went by, it still surprises me that I was able to avoid the languages these programs I loved were written in. It took almost 19 years to finally see a line of code -- 2 years ago this month, studying Medical Sciences at Western University, in my first computer science course. Within the first few weeks, I realized it was something I was good at, and over the next few months, it caused me to reconsider my degree all together. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I attend the University of Waterloo, studying Computer Engineering. I&amp;#39;ve worked two jobs in the tech industry over the year and a half I&amp;#39;ve attended. I&amp;#39;ve written countless lines of code since my first, and hope to never stop. There&amp;#39;s more to programming than just logic puzzles, which is how I initially grasped it; when you start to group together small functions, it becomes apparent that these systems can tell you much more than just fizz or buzz.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of AI, using a collection of varied, semi-unique inputs, finding a pattern, and applying them as a human might, is what deeply interests me. As we spend our time clicking away on Facebook, Twitter, Reddit, a computer somewhere miles away tracks these movements, records them, and ties them to an internet version of ourselves. Over time, these recorded decisions add up. A computer can use this info and relate it to other info it gathers (ie. clicking on a link for baseballs and one for t-shirts may result in receiving an ad for baseball t-shirts!). As a result, feeds are tailored so they list what interests you most, without the need to explicitly tell it anything. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I dream to work on: a system which anonymously monitors ones inputs, uses the patterns found, and responds based upon them. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; a video game that responds to your skill level by progressively increasing or decreasing the difficulty, ensuring for the most balanced play-through possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a system which monitors the market, which can be used to buy and sell investments (ie stocks, real estate) using the patterns it has gathered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an application that learns how to distinguish important phrases or words, which can be used for effectively indexing and sorting data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although slightly specific ideas, they can be stretched and built upon. One day, most of the systems we use will be able to utilize this pattern-finding to improve their accuracy. In other words, you will be able to ask your house for a coffee, and it won’t be all that weird when it puts in 0.834 teaspoons of sugar and 21mL of cream. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may have gone off on a tangent, but if it isn’t already obvious, I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; technology. Software is nearly limitless; every day, someone, somewhere, has created something that can automate a process that would take a human a considerable amount of time to complete. The compilation of these automations can both improve the lives of others and promote the expansion of humanity&amp;#39;s knowledge. When these tools are combined with also ever-improving hardware, you&amp;#39;re in for a hell of a ride. The sheer number of examples we have available would definitely assert that faster computers, vaster networks, and smarter AIs are the future -- one I&amp;#39;m sprinting towards.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A New Year, 2016</title>
   <link href="http://www.andrewladd.co/2016/01/06/the-beginning/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.andrewladd.co/2016/01/06/the-beginning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, and welcome to my wall of writing. Here I hope to accomplish a few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk about what I&amp;#39;m working on, what interests me, or what&amp;#39;s been on my mind. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill a gap in my writing-less life. I may type words every day, but not very formally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record my experiences, so maybe someone else can learn from my perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, 2016, I hope to produce two posts for each month. This number may increase or decrease, depending on how crazy the months get, but I hope to hit 24 posts by December 31st of this year. Wish me luck, and I&amp;#39;ll see you in my first post. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
