<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Andrew Ladd</title>
 <link href="http://www.andrewladd.co/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.andrewladd.co/"/>
 <updated>2016-01-11T02:06:26-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.andrewladd.co</id>
 <author>
   <name>Andrew Ladd</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>My technological life & why I love the internet</title>
   <link href="http://www.andrewladd.co/2016/01/09/i-heart-tech/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.andrewladd.co/2016/01/09/i-heart-tech</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is where I should address how my internet life began, and how I&amp;#39;m maturing to a contributing force.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea, that a collection of varied, semi-unique inputs can be interpreted as a pattern -- and over time -- as something resembling a human, is what deeply interests me. As we spend our time clicking away on Facebook, Twitter, Reddit, a computer somewhere miles away tracks these movements, records them, and ties them to an internet version of ourselves.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over time&lt;/strong&gt;, these recorded decisions add up. A computer can use this info and relate it to other info it gathers (ie. clicking on a link for baseballs and one for t-shirts may result in receiving an ad for baseball t-shirts!). As a result, computers are able to tailor the feeds you see daily to your tastes, without the need to explicitly tell it anything. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In time, this is what I dream to work on: a system which anonymously monitors your life, uses the patterns it finds, and is able to respond based on the info it has. For example, an autonomous house:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon arrival, the lighting is set in the most-used rooms to an appropriate level, and ensures the temperature is comfortable. Depending on those present and the time of day, it can play music related to everyone&amp;#39;s tastes and ensure it is contextually appropriate. It is able to respond to voice commands, and can relay important news – automatically or by prompt – depending on how important that news is to the user. Using the location of the user’s cell phone (or some other device), it can turn on &amp;amp; off lighting as wanted, and can monitor noise and brightness levels to reflect that of the devices that are outputting media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although a short example, the limits of current technology aren’t far off from probing the lives we live. One day, systems will be rigid enough to withstand mass-consumer usage. In other words, you will be able to ask your house for a coffee, and it won’t be all that weird. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may have gone off on a tangent, but if it isn’t already obvious, it is why &lt;em&gt;I love technology&lt;/em&gt;. Software is nearly limitless; every day, someone, somewhere, has created something that can automate a process that would take a human a considerable amount of time to complete. The compilation of these automations can both improve the lives of others and promote the expansion of knowledge of humanity. It may seem drastic, but the sheer number of examples one could provide would most definitely assert that computers, programming, and artificial intelligence is the future. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all a good day, to all a good night.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A New Year, 2016</title>
   <link href="http://www.andrewladd.co/2016/01/06/the-beginning/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.andrewladd.co/2016/01/06/the-beginning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the beginning of an age, and AGE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, you know what I said!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still some space that needs filled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MORE SPACE TO FILL&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
